Guide to the Corcoran Gallery of Art and Corcoran College of Art + Design, Corcoran Gallery of Art financial records, 1872-1988 COR0004.0.RG
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Miscellaneous subjects, 1934-1989; Series 14
  - Dean of the School: Applicants' Listing, 1980; Series 14 (Box 22, Folder 59)
  - Dean of the School: Candidate Evaluations, 1980; Series 14 (Box 22, Folder 60)
  - Dean of the School: Faculty Search Committee, 1980; Series 14 (Box 22, Folder 61)
  - Dean of the School: Final Candidates Information, 1980; Series 14 (Box 22, Folders 62-66)
  - Registrar (School): Fall, 1980; Series 14 (Box 22, Folder 67)
  - Secretary to Director of Development: Summer, 1980; Series 14 (Box 22, Folder 68)
  - Shop Assistant: Spring, 1980; Series 14 (Box 22, Folder 69)
  - Three Institution Proposal: Staff Position: Spring, 1980; Series 14 (Box 22, Folder 70)
  - (School) Director of Extension Programs: Fall (223 Applications 6 Interviewed), 1981; Series 14 (Box 22, Folder 71)
  - (School) Director of Extension Programs: Fall, 1981; Series 14 (Box 22, Folders 72-73)
  - Registrar (School): Fall (199 Applications 3 Interviewed), 1981; Series 14 (Box 22, Folder 74)
  - By-Law Policies, 1971-1972; Series 14 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Bank Accounts, 1972-1977; Series 14 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Gifts, circa 1975; Series 14 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Finance Committee, 1977; Series 14 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Letters, 1976-1977; Series 14 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - EDP Technology, circa 1970-1980; Series 14 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Estate of Fannie S. Eanes, circa 1974; Series 14 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous, 1975; Series 14 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous, 1974; Series 14 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous, 1973; Series 14 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous, 1972; Series 14 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous, 1970-1971; Series 14 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Committee Assignments, 1985-1989; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Board of Trustees, 1989; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Board of Trustees, 1986-1987; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Investment & Finance Committee Members List, 1986; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - After Event Work Sheets, 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Art Sales & Rental Gallery, Undated; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Association of Art Museum Directors, 1987; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Audit File, 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Budget Information, 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Capital Campaign, 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Coopers & Lybrand Mailings File, 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Corcoran Cafe, 1984; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Corcoran Shop Sales, 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Cultural Alliance, 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Dudley Fund Lecture, 1987-1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Facility Use, 1983; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - [General Total Institutional Financial Information reports], circa 1987; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Friends of the Corcoran, 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Gallery Donation for Gala Event Cultural Alliance, circa 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Grants & Funds, 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Group Admissions Infor., 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Gwen Goffe Acting Director File, 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - Gwen's Correspondence/RSVP, 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - In-House Calendar of Events, 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - Interesting Reading, 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - Johnson Lemon Correspondence, 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - Memorandums, 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - Memo-Exec. Comm. (Budget), 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 29)
  - Memorandums-Sally Smith, 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 30)
  - PR News Releases, 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - Personnel File, 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 32)
  - Tax Exempt Status Requests Mailed, 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 33)
  - Trustee Luncheon Invoices, 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 34)
  - Vendor Information File, circa 1985-1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 35)
  - Vendor File Information, 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 36)
  - Vendor Listing, 1989; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 37)
  - Weekly Attendance Reports, 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 38)
  - Women's Committee Ball, 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 39)
  - Working Copies of Comm. Minutes, 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 40)
  - Women's Committee, 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 41)
  - Investment & Finance Comm Correspondence, 1988; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 42)
  - Art School Committee Mtg, 1987; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 43)
  - AS Committee, 1988 May 31; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 44)
  - Committee on Works of Art, 1987; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 45)
  - Ms. Goffe Art, 1988 May 11; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 46)
  - Investment & Finance Comm. Mtg, 1987 July; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 47)
  - Investment & Finance Comm. (Budget), 1987 July 8; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 48)
  - Budget Papers, 1987 July 8; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 49)
  - Budget Papers, 1987 July 8; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 50)
  - Budget Papers, 1987 July 8; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 51)
  - Ms. Goffe Finance Comm, 1987 July 8; Series 14 (Box 25, Folder 52)
- Personnel office records, 1944-1981; Series 15
  Contains history files on individual staff members, organized alphabetically. Also includes general/miscellaneous personnel records, arranged chronologically. Materials record a variety of employment information; hiring, promotions, raises, salaries, and resignations/terminations in employment. One file box of index cards on staff members, arranged alphabetically, is also included. The cards are most complete for the 1950s and 1960s, but they do continue to record scattered information on staff members into the mid-1970s.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Files in this series are closed for 50 years from date of record creation.
  - Staff files: A-W, 1944-1981; Series 15 (Box 14, Folders 45-110)
  - Personnel Folders: W - Misc., 1944-1973; Series 15 (Box 22, Folders 75-99)
- Unprocessed records, Circa 1980s-2014; COR0004.RG Series 16
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of the Trustees Of The Corcoran Gallery Of Art, April 26, 2022 (accession 2022.025)
  The recodrs in this series are closed for 50 years from date of record creation. If you have questions about the creation date of materials in this series please contact Special Collections staff.
  Arranged in no particular order
  The boxes in this series are restricted and not yet open for reearch. The only details knowns are from what is written on the boxes. From this information this series contains financial records including financial ledgers, audit records, grant materials, correspondence. The date range is circa 1980-2014.
  - LEDGERS, B and G SCRAPBOOK, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-2008-01)
    General
    Receipt date (when the item arrived at off-site storage) 2008 February 27
  - LEDGERS, LEGAL DOCS, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-2008-02)
  - FY07 MONTHLY BOARD REPORTS, 2006-2007; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-2009-05)
    Receipt date (when the item arrived at off-site storage) 2009 June 15
  - FY06 monthly board reports, 2005 September - February 2006; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-2009-06)
  - SUBJECT FILES, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-2013-07)
    Receipt date (when the item arrived at off-site storage) 2013 March 26
  - Herman Trust grant receivable, 2003-2011; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-2013-28)
  - David Dorsey files, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-2013-105)
    Receipt date (when the item arrived at off-site storage) 2013 December 05
  - legal docs, voided checks, 2006-2008; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-2013-99)
  - 101 CAMPAIGN, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-2014-001)
    Receipt date (when the item arrived at off-site storage) 2014 March 21
  - No title provided, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-2014-002)
  - INVESTMENTS AND MINUTES, 2004-2009; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-2014-003)
  - WC BALL INVEST SCHOOL REV and reconciliation, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-2014-005)
  - PNC CC Recons alnduri-hartwell, 2012-2013; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-2014-009)
  - SSCR REPORTS, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-2014-238)
    Receipt date (when the item arrived at off-site storage) 2014 September 10
  - bank receipts, loomis, pnc deposits FY2014, 2013-2014; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-2014-247)
    Receipt date (when the item arrived at off-site storage) 2014 October 18
  - Executive and full board meeting materials and minutes from finance, Circa 1986; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-107)
    Receipt date (when the item arrived at off-site storage) 2014 October 02
  - No title provided, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-95)
    Receipt date (when the item arrived at off-site storage) 1995 June 20
  - Financial ledgers, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-79)
    Receipt date (when the item arrived at off-site storage) 1997 April 16
  - Financial ledgers, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-90)
  - Endowment reports investments transactions, 1981-1989; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-096)
  - Transaction statements endowment info; transaction statements, 1981-1984; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-131)
  - No title provided, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-36)
  - FY89 Controller files, 1988-1989; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-61)
  - Financial ledgers, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-81)
  - Financial ledgers, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-82)
  - Financial ledgers, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-85)
  - No title provided, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-72)
  - No title provided, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-25)
  - Finance office general correspondence minutes and correspondence com meeting FY86, 1985-1986; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-109)
  - No title provided, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-163)
  - Financial files 84.28, 1980-1982; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-60)
  - Financial files, 1980-1982; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-47)
  - Finance ledgers, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-83)
  - Grants, misc. time sheets?, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-37)
  - Exhibition grant inof and other grants, circa 1981-1985; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-39)
  - FY86 Exhibition Grants, 1985-1986; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-26)
  - No title provided, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-165)
  - Exhibition grants info, 1984-1985; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-38)
  - No title provided, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-157)
  - No title provided, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-160)
  - challenge grants exhibition grants restricted funds FY82-83, 1981-1983; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-42)
  - FY82-88 Grant Files NEA, 1981-1989; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-269)
  - No title provided, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-265)
  - No title provided, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-239)
  - No title provided, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-243)
  - Grant Files, 1980-1989; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-177)
  - petty cash and affordable art and trustees, 1981-1987; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-186)
  - No title provided, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-022)
  - Audit FY88, 1987-1988; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-222)
  - No title provided, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-142)
  - Reports, Circa 1985; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-116)
  - Audit info, Undated; COR0004.0-RG Series 16 (Box RG4-129)
  - TRANSITION DOCS FY2015 FY2016, 2014-2015; COR0004.RG Series 16 (Box UP1)